Register of the Polish Information Center (New York, N.Y.) Records
Hoover Institution Archives
- CLIPPINGS, 1942-1945 (Box 4)
  - G. Atlantic Charter, Four Freedoms, Lend-Lease (Karta Atlantycka, Four Freedoms, Lend-Lease) (Box 33)
    - 1943
      - June (Box 34)
        - 1-15
          - Atlantic (Folder 34: 1)
          - Midwest (Folder 34: 2)
          - Pacific (Folder 34: 3)
        - 16-30
          - Atlantic (Folder 34: 4)
          - Midwest (Folder 34: 5)
          - Pacific (Folder 34: 6)
      - July
        - 1-15
          - Atlantic (Folder 34: 7)
          - Midwest (Folder 34: 8)
        - 16-31
          - Atlantic (Folder 34: 9)
          - Midwest (Folder 34: 10)
          - Pacific (Folder 34: 11)
      - August
        - 1-15
          - Atlantic (Folder 34: 12)
          - Midwest (Box-folder 35: 1)
          - Pacific (Folder 35: 2)
        - 16-31
          - Atlantic (Folder 35: 3-4)
          - Midwest (Folder 35: 5-6)
          - Pacific (Folder 35: 7)
      - September (Box 36)
        - 1-4 (Folder 36: 1)
        - 5-8 (Folder 36: 2)
        - 9-10 (Folder 36: 3)
        - 11-12 (Folder 36: 4)
        - 13-15 (Folder 36: 5)
        - 16-19 (Folder 36: 6)
        - 20-23 (Folder 36: 7)
        - 24-30 (Box-folder 37: 1)
      - October
        - 1-4 (Folder 37: 2)
        - 5-10 (Folder 37: 3)
        - 11-15 (Folder 37: 4)
        - 16-31 (Folder 37: 5)
      - November (Folder 37: 6)
      - December (Folder 37: 7)
  - H. Post-war Europe (Europa po zakonczeniu dzialan wojennych) (Box 38)
    - 1942
      - November (Folder 38: 1)
      - December
        - 1-15 (Folder 38: 2)
        - 15-31
          - Atlantic (Folder 38: 3)
          - Midwest (Folder 38: 4)
          - Pacific (Folder 38: 5)
    - 1943
      - January
        - - Midwest, 1-15 (Folder 38: 6)
        - 16-31
          - Atlantic (Folder 38: 7)
          - Midwest (Box-folder 39: 1)
          - Pacific (Folder 39: 2)
      - February
        - 1-15
          - General
            - Atlantic (Folder 39: 3)
            - Midwest (Folder 39: 4)
            - Pacific (Folder 39: 5)
          - Jewish (Folder 39: 6)
        - 16-28
          - Atlantic (Folder 39: 7)
          - Midwest (Folder 39: 8)
          - Pacific (Folder 39: 9)
      - March
        - General
          - Atlantic (Folder 39: 10)
          - Midwest (Folder 39: 11)
        - Jewish (Folder 39: 12)
      - April
        - 1-15
          - Atlantic (Folder 39: 13)
          - Midwest (Folder 39: 14)
          - Pacific (Folder 39: 15)
        - 16-30 (Box 40)
          - General
            - Atlantic (Folder 40: 1)
            - Midwest (Folder 40: 2)
            - Pacific (Folder 40: 3)
          - Jewish (Folder 40: 4)
      - May
        - 1-15
          - General
            - Atlantic (Folder 40: 5)
            - Midwest (Folder 40: 6)
            - Pacific (Folder 40: 7)
          - Jewish (Folder 40: 8)
        - 16-31 (Box 41)
          - Atlantic (Folder 41: 1)
          - Midwest (Folder 41: 2)
          - Pacific (Folder 41: 3)
      - June
        - 1-15
          - Atlantic (Folder 41: 4)
          - Midwest (Folder 41: 5)
          - Pacific (Folder 41: 6)
        - 16-30
          - Atlantic (Folder 41: 7)
          - Jewish (Folder 41: 8)
      - July
        - 1-15 (Folder 41: 9)
        - 16-31 (Folder 41: 10)
      - August
        - 1-15 (Folder 41: 11)
        - 16-31 (Folder 41: 12)
      - September-November (Folder 41: 13)
    - 1944 (Folder 41: 14)
  - I. Post-war United States and Pacific (Stany Zjednoczone i obszar Pacyfiku po zakonczeniu dzialan wojennych)
    - 1942 December (Folder 42: 1)
    - 1943
      - January 16-31
        - Atlantic (Folder 42: 2)
        - Midwest (Folder 42: 3)
        - Pacific (Folder 42: 4)
      - February
        - 1-15
          - Atlantic (Folder 42: 5)
          - Midwest (Folder 42: 6)
          - Pacific (Folder 42: 7)
        - 16-28
          - Atlantic (Folder 42: 8)
          - Midwest (Folder 42: 9)
          - Pacific (Folder 42: 10)
      - March (Box 43)
        - 1-15
          - General
            - Atlantic (Folder 43: 1)
            - Midwest (Folder 43: 2)
            - Pacific (Folder 43: 3)
          - Jewish (Folder 43: 4)
        - 16-30
          - Atlantic (Folder 43: 5)
          - Midwest (Folder 43: 6)
          - Pacific (Folder 43: 7)
      - April
        - 1-15
          - Atlantic (Folder 43: 8)
          - Midwest (Folder 43: 9)
        - 16-30
          - General
            - Atlantic (Folder 43: 10)
            - Midwest (Folder 43: 11)
            - Pacific (Folder 43: 12)
          - Jewish (Folder 43: 13)
      - May (Box 44)
        - 1-15
          - Atlantic (Folder 44: 1)
          - Midwest (Folder 44: 2)
          - Pacific (Folder 44: 3)
        - 16-31
          - Atlantic (Folder 44: 4)
          - Midwest (Folder 44: 5)
          - Pacific (Folder 44: 6)
      - June
        - 1-15
          - Atlantic (Folder 44: 7)
          - Midwest (Folder 44: 8)
          - Pacific (Folder 44: 9)
        - 16-30
          - General
            - Atlantic (Folder 44: 10-12)
            - Midwest (Folder 45: 1)
            - Pacific (Folder 45: 2)
          - Jewish (Folder 45: 3)
      - July
        - 1-15
          - Atlantic (Folder 45: 4)
          - Midwest (Folder 45: 5)
        - 16-31
          - Atlantic (Folder 45: 6)
          - Midwest (Folder 45: 7)
          - Pacific (Folder 45: 8)
      - August
        - 1-15
          - Atlantic (Folder 45: 9)
          - Midwest (Folder 45: 10)
          - Pacific (Folder 45: 11)
        - 16-31
          - Atlantic (Folder 45: 12)
          - Midwest (Folder 45: 13)
          - Pacific (Folder 45: 14)
      - September 1-15 (Box 46)
        - Atlantic (Folder 46: 1)
        - Midwest (Folder 46: 2)
        - Pacific (Folder 46: 3)
      - October
        - 1-16
          - Atlantic (Folder 46: 4)
          - Midwest (Folder 46: 5)
          - Pacific (Folder 46: 6)
        - 17-24
          - Atlantic (Folder 46: 7)
          - Midwest (Folder 46: 8)
          - Pacific (Folder 46: 9)
        - 25-31
          - Atlantic (Folder 46: 10)
          - Atlantic (Box-folder 47: 1)
          - Midwest (Folder 47: 2)
          - Pacific (Folder 47: 3)
      - November 1-15
        - Atlantic (Folder 47: 4)
        - Midwest (Folder 47: 5)
        - Pacific (Folder 47: 6)
      - December 15-31
        - Atlantic (Folder 47: 7)
        - Pacific (Folder 47: 8)
    - 1944
      - January-March (Folder 47: 9)
      - November (Folder 47: 10)
  - J. Profiles of journals (Charaktersytyki pism), 1943
    - January (Folder 48: 1)
    - February (Folder 48: 2)
    - March (Folder 48: 3)
    - April-May (Folder 48: 4)
    - September-November (Folder 48: 5)
  - K. Profiles of journalists (Charakterystyki publicystow)
    - 1943
      - January (Folder 48: 6)
      - February (Folder 48: 7)
      - March (Folder 48: 8)
      - April-May (Folder 48: 9)
      - October (Folder 48: 10)
      - November (Folder 48: 11)
      - December (Folder 48: 12)
    - 1944
      - January-March (Folder 48: 13)
      - November (Folder 48: 14)
  - LA. Jewish affairs in American press (Sprawy zydowskie w prasie amerykanskiej)
    - 1943
      - June
        - 1-15
          - General
            - Atlantic (Folder 48: 15)
            - Pacific (Folder 48: 16)
          - Jewish (Folder 48: 17)
        - - Atlantic, 16-30 (Folder 48: 18)
      - July
        - 1-15
          - Atlantic (Folder 48: 19)
          - Jewish (Folder 48: 20)
        - - Jews, rescue plans, 16-31
          - General
            - Atlantic (Folder 48: 21)
            - Pacific (Folder 48: 22)
          - Jewish (Folder 48: 23)
      - August (Box 49)
        - 1-15
          - General
            - Atlantic (Folder 49: 1)
            - Midwest (Folder 49: 2)
            - Pacific (Folder 49: 3)
          - Jewish (Folder 49: 4)
        - 16-31
          - General
            - Atlantic (Folder 49: 5)
            - Midwest (Folder 49: 6)
            - Pacific (Folder 49: 7)
          - Jewish (Folder 49: 8)
      - September 1-15
        - General
          - Atlantic (Folder 49: 9)
          - Pacific (Folder 49: 10)
          - Jewish (Folder 49: 11)
      - October (Folder 49: 12)
      - November (Folder 49: 13)
    - 1944 (Folder 49: 14)
  - LB. Jewish affairs in Jewish press (Sprawy zydowskie w prasie amerykanskiej)
    - General.
      Includes reports on protest action against extermination of Jews in Europe
      - 1942
        - November 25-30 (Folder 49: 15)
        - December 1-10 (Folder 49: 16)
      - 1942 October - 1943 February (Box-folder 50: 1)
      - 1943
        - February (Folder 50: 2)
        - March
          - 1-15 (Folder 50: 3)
          - 16-30 (Folder 50: 4)
        - April 15-30 (Folder 50: 5)
        - May 1-15 (Folder 50: 6)
        - June 1-15 (Folder 50: 7)
        - July-August (Folder 50: 8)
        - October (Box 51)
          - 1-15 (Folder 51: 1)
          - 16-31 (Folder 51: 2)
        - November
          - 1-15 (Folder 51: 3)
          - 16-30 (Folder 51: 4)
      - 1944
        - January (Folder 51: 5)
        - March 16-31 (Folder 51: 6-7)
        - September 16-30 (Box-folder 52: 1-2)
        - October
          - 1-15 (Folder 52: 3-4)
          - 16-31 (Folder 52: 5-6)
      - 1945 (Box 53)
        - January
          - 1-15 (Folder 53: 1-2)
          - 16-31 (Folder 53: 3-4)
        - March 1-15 (Folder 53: 5-6)
    - Releases
      - F8, 1942 May-November (Folder 54: 1)
      - F9, 1942 November-December (Folder 54: 2)
      - F10, 1942 August-December (Folder 54: 3)
      - F12, 1942 April - 1943 January (Folder 54: 4)
      - F14, 1942 September - 1943 January (Folder 54: 5)
      - F19, 1942 October - 1943 February (Folder 54: 6)
      - F21, 1943 February-March (Box-folder 55: 1)
      - F22, 1942 December - 1943 March (Folder 55: 2)
      - F25, 1943 January-March (Folder 55: 3)
      - F32, 1943 February-May (Folder 55: 4)
      - F33, 1943 March-May (Folder 55: 5)
      - F41, 1943 April-July (Folder 55: 6)
      - F44, 1943 May-August (Folder 55: 7)
      - F51, 1943 June-October (Folder 55: 8)
      - F52, 1943 July-October (Folder 55: 9)
      - F54, 1943 September-October (Folder 55: 10)
      - F66, 1943 October - 1944 January (Folder 55: 11)
      - F58, 1943 November (Box-folder 56: 1)
      - F59, 1943 July-November (Folder 56: 2)
      - F60, 1943 August-October (Folder 56: 3)
      - F61, 1943 September-December (Folder 56: 4)
      - F62, 1943 September-December (Folder 56: 5)
      - F63, 1943 October-December (Folder 56: 6)
      - F64, 1943 October-December (Folder 56: 7)
      - F65, 1943 December - 1944 January (Folder 56: 8)
      - F67-68, 1944 January (Folder 56: 9)
      - F69, 1943 October - 1944 February (Folder 56: 10)
      - F70, 1943 October - 1944 February (Box-folder 57: 1)
      - F73, 1943 December - 1944 March (Folder 57: 2)
      - F74, 1943 November - 1944 March (Folder 57: 3)
      - F91, 1944 July (Folder 57: 4)
      - F92, 1944 July (Folder 57: 5)
      - F95, 1944 August (Folder 57: 6)
      - F96, 1944 August (Folder 57: 7)
  - M. International relief (Miedzynarodowa pomoc) (Box 58)
    - 1943
      - June
        - 1-15
          - Atlantic (Folder 58: 1)
          - Midwest (Folder 58: 2)
          - Pacific (Folder 58: 3)
        - 16-30
          - Atlantic (Folder 58: 4)
          - Pacific (Folder 58: 5)
      - July
        - - Atlantic, 1-15 (Folder 58: 6)
        - 16-31
          - Atlantic (Folder 58: 7)
          - Midwest (Folder 58: 8)
          - Pacific (Folder 58: 9)
      - August
        - 1-15
          - Atlantic (Folder 58: 10)
          - Midwest (Folder 58: 11)
        - 16-31
          - Atlantic (Folder 58: 12)
          - Midwest (Folder 58: 13)
      - October (Folder 58: 14)
      - November 1-15 (Folder 58: 15)
      - December (Folder 58: 16)
    - 1944 (Folder 58: 17)
  - O. Peace (Pokoj) (Box 59)
    - 1942
      - November (Folder 59: 1)
      - December
        - 1-15 (Folder 59: 2-3)
        - 16-31 (Folder 59: 4-5)
    - 1943
      - January
        - 1-15 (Folder 59: 6-7)
        - 16-31 (Folder 59: 8-9)
      - February 1-15 (Box-folder 60: 1)
      - March
        - 1-15
          - Atlantic (Folder 60: 2)
          - Pacific (Folder 60: 3)
        - 16-31 (Folder 60: 4)
      - April
        - 1-15 (Folder 60: 5)
        - 16-30 (Folder 60: 6)
      - May
        - 1-15 (Folder 60: 7)
        - 16-30 (Folder 60: 8)
      - June (Box-folder 61: 1)
      - July (Folder 61: 2)
      - August (Folder 61: 3)
      - October (Folder 61: 4)
      - December (Folder 61: 5)
  - R. France, Italy, North Africa, Middle East (Francja, Wlochy, Afryka Polnocna i Bliski Wschod)
    - 1943
      - October (Folder 61: 6)
      - November (Folder 61: 7)
      - December (Folder 61: 8)
    - 1944
      - March (Folder 61: 9)
      - April (Folder 61: 10)
      - November (Folder 61: 11)
  - T. Balkans and Yugoslavia (Balkany i Jugoslawia)
    - 1943
      - October (Folder 61: 12)
      - November (Folder 61: 13)
    - 1944
      - March (Folder 61: 14)
      - November (Folder 61: 15)
  - V. Vatican and Catholic world (Watykan i swiat katolicki), 1943
    - July-August (Folder 61: 16)
    - September-November (Folder 61: 17)
- CORRESPONDENCE, 1940-1945 (Box 62)
  - General
    - General
      - 1943
        - September (Folder 62: 1)
        - October (Folder 62: 2)
        - November (Folder 62: 3)
      - 1944
        - January (Folder 62: 4)
        - March (Folder 62: 5)
        - April (Folder 62: 6)
    - Address file
      - General (Folder 62: 7)
      - Polish diplomatic outpost (Folder 62: 8)
    - Christmas cards (Folder 62: 9)
    - Envelopes (Folder 62: 10)
    - Postcards, 1944 (Folder 62: 11)
  - Erdman, Jan (Polskie Centrum Informacyjne, Publishing Department), 1944 (Box 63)
    - January-March (Folder 63: 1)
    - April-June (Folder 63: 2)
    - July-September (Folder 63: 3)
    - October-December (Folder 63: 4)
  - Frydler, W. W., 1944 July-December (Folder 63: 5)
  - Inter-Allied Information Centre
    - 1940 (Folder 63: 6)
    - 1941
      - January-April (Folder 63: 7)
      - May-August (Folder 63: 8)
      - September-October (Folder 63: 9)
      - November-December (Folder 63: 10)
    - 1942
      - January-March (Folder 64: 1)
      - April-June (Folder 64: 2)
      - July-August (Folder 64: 3)
  - Junosza, Jozef
    - General
      - 1943 (Folder 64: 4)
      - 1944 (Folder 64: 5)
      - 1945 (Folder 64: 6)
    - Unanswered mail (Folder 64: 7)
  - Kozmian, Henryk
    - 1943
      - September-October (Folder 64: 8)
      - November-December (Folder 64: 9)
    - 1944
      - January (Folder 64: 10)
      - February (Folder 64: 11)
      - March (Folder 64: 12)
      - April (Folder 64: 13)
  - Mieczyslawska, Aniela (Box 65)
    - 1943
      - June-September (Folder 65: 1)
      - October-December (Folder 65: 2)
    - 1944
      - January-March (Folder 65: 3)
      - April-June (Folder 65: 4)
      - July-September (Folder 65: 5)
      - October-December (Folder 65: 6)
  - Musicians and singers, 1943-1944 (Folder 65: 7)
  - News Bulletin on East European Affairs
    - 1940 (Folder 65: 8)
    - 1941
      - January-April (Folder 65: 9)
      - May-October (Folder 65: 10)
    - 1942 February-May (Folder 65: 11)
  - Podoski, Roman, 1944 and 1946 (Folder 65: 12)
  - Poland. Konsulat (Chicago)
    - 1940 (Folder 65: 13)
    - 1941
      - January-April (Folder 65: 14)
      - May-August (Folder 65: 15)
  - Stowarzyszenie Technikow Polskich, 1943 (Folder 65: 16)
  - Walczak, Jan (Box 66)
    - Carbon copies
      - 1943 June-December (Folder 66: 1)
      - 1944
        - January-March (Folder 66: 2)
        - April-June (Folder 66: 3)
        - July-September (Folder 66: 4)
        - October-December (Folder 66: 5)
    - Originals, 1944 (Folder 66: 6)
  - Werminska, Wanda, 1943 (Folder 66: 7)
  - Ziffer, Bernard, 1944 November-December (Folder 66: 8)
- OFFICE FILES, 1941-1945
  - General
    - General (Folder 66: 9)
    - Budget file, 1941-1944 (Folder 66: 10)
    - Certificates of employment, 1945 June (Folder 66: 11)
    - Newspaper and magazine subscriptions (Folder 66: 12)
    - Organizational charts (Folder 66: 13)
    - Reviews (Box 67)
      - Book reviews, 1942-1943 (Folder 67: 1)
      - Press reviews
        - Daily Press Reports, New York
          - 1943
            - May (Folder 67: 2)
            - June (Folder 67: 3)
            - July (Folder 67: 4)
            - August (Folder 67: 5)
            - September (Folder 67: 6)
            - October (Folder 67: 7)
            - November (Folder 67: 8)
            - December (Folder 67: 9)
          - 1944
            - January (Folder 67: 10)
            - February (Box-folder 68: 1)
            - March (Folder 68: 2)
        - Przeglad Prasy Periodycznej
          - General
            - 1943 May-September (Folder 68: 3)
            - 1944 January-February (Folder 68: 4)
          - Holograph, 1943 April (Folder 68: 5)
          - Typescripts, 1943
            - April (Folder 68: 6)
            - May (Folder 68: 7)
- PRINTED MATTER, 1942-1945
  - General. War and Peace Aims: Extracts from Statements of United Nations Leaders, New York, 1943 (Folder 68: 8)
  - Newspaper issues
    - American, 1944 (Folder 68: 9)
    - Polish-American, 1943
      - General (Folder 68: 10)
      - Nowy Swiat (Folder 68: 11-14)
    - Russian-American - Novaia Zaria, San Francisco, 1942 (Folder 68: 15)
- REPORTS, 1943-1944 (Box 69)
  - General
    - 1943
      - September (Folder 69: 1)
      - October (Folder 69: 2)
      - November (Folder 69: 3)
      - December (Folder 69: 4)
    - 1944
      - January (Folder 69: 5)
      - February (Folder 69: 6)
      - April (Folder 69: 7)
      - July (Folder 69: 8)
      - October (Folder 69: 9)
  - American Friends of Poland, 1944 (Folder 69: 10)
  - Catholic circles, n.d. (Folder 69: 11)
  - Film Department, 1944 (Folder 69: 12)
  - German Department, 1944
    - General (Folder 69: 13)
    - Germans in the United States (Folder 69: 14)
  - Jewish circles, 1943 July (Folder 69: 15)
  - Jews, Resettlement of, 1944 January (Folder 69: 16)
  - Katolicka Agencja Prasowa, 1944 (Folder 69: 17)
  - Polish-American press (Folder 69: 18)
  - Polish propaganda in the United States
    - - Tadeusz Hoinko (Press Department), 1942 (Folder 69: 19)
    - 1943 (Folder 69: 20)
    - 1944 (Folder 69: 21)
  - Soviet occupation of Eastern Poland, Economic impact of (Folder 69: 22)
- SUBJECT FILE, 1936-1952
  - America First (Folder 69: 23-25)
  - American Council on Public Affairs (Folder 69: 26)
  - American Vigilant Intelligence Federation (Folder 69: 27)
  - Appreciate America (Folder 69: 28)
  - Biddle, Anthony (Folder 69: 29)
  - Bor-Komorowski, Tadeusz. Polish-American clippings (Box 70)
    - 1945 (Folder 70: 1)
    - 1946 (Folder 70: 2-6)
  - Bullit, William, address on Poland, 1943 September 12 (Folder 70: 7)
  - Cairo Conference., (1943)
    See Teheran Conference (1943)
  - Central European Union, 1943-1945 (Folder 70: 8)
  - Chicago Committee to Defend America by Aiding the Allies
    - General (Folder 70: 9)
    - Brochures (Folder 70: 10)
    - Leaflets (Folder 70: 11)
    - Memorabilia (Folder 70: 12)
  - Dewey, Thomas, E., 1944 September (Folder 70: 13)
  - Fight for Freedom (Box 71)
    - General (Folder 71: 1)
    - Lindbergh, Charles, Response to (Folder 71: 2)
  - Friends of Aid to Russia (Folder 71: 3)
  - Gdynia (Poland) (Folder 71: 4)
  - German American National Alliance (Folder 71: 5)
  - Great Britain. Parliament - Debates on Poland, 1944-1945 (Folder 71: 6)
  - Greek War Relief (Folder 71: 7)
  - Grunwald.
    See Tannenberg, Battle of, 1410
    - General
      - General (Folder 71: 8)
      - Clippings
        - 1943 (Folder 71: 9)
        - 1944 (Folder 71: 10)
        - 1945 (Folder 71: 11)
    - Warsaw Ghetto
      - 1943 (Folder 71: 12)
      - 1944 (Folder 71: 13)
  - Junosza, Jozef
    - 1943-1944 (Folder 71: 14)
    - 1945 (Folder 71: 15)
  - Katyn Forest Massacre, 1940
    - General (Folder 71: 16)
    - Press clippings (Folder 71: 17)
  - Kopernik, Mikolaj. Typescript of a book in German, n.d. (Folder 71: 18)
  - Kot, Stanislaw, Arrest of, 1938 (Folder 71: 19)
  - Kwapinski, Jan - Trip to the United States, 1943 December (Folder 71: 20)
  - Lange-Orlemanski affair, 1944 May-June (Folder 71: 21)
  - Mikolajczyk, Stanislaw - Trips, 1944 (Box 72)
    - Soviet Union (Folder 72: 1-3)
    - United States (Folder 72: 4)
  - Peace, 1944 August-September (Folder 72: 5)
  - Poland
    - Boundaries - Soviet Union
      - Ethnicity (Folder 72: 6)
      - Polish-American meeting, Chicago, 1944 (Folder 72: 7)
    - Children
      - General
        - German-occupied Poland (Folder 72: 8)
        - Soviet Union and Middle East (Folder 72: 9)
      - Brochure, Children in Bondage.
        Clippings and manuscript notes collected for various chapters
        - General (Folder 72: 10)
        - 1. German policy in occupied Poland (Folder 72: 11)
        - 2. Teaching of hatred against Poles (Folder 72: 12)
        - 3. Destruction of social reforms and institutions (Folder 72: 13)
        - 4. Destruction of religion, culture, education (Folder 72: 14)
        - 5. Economic exploitation (Folder 72: 15)
        - 6. Kidnapping of population (Folder 72: 16)
        - 7. Forced labor (Folder 72: 17)
        - 8. Demoralization of youth (Folder 72: 18)
        - 9. Terror - Collective response (Box 73)
          - General (Folder 73: 1)
          - a. Children (Folder 73: 2)
          - b. Women (Folder 73: 3)
        - 10. Family life under Nazi rule (Folder 73: 4)
        - 11. Children in ghettos (Folder 73: 5)
    - Concentration camps - Auschwitz (Folder 73: 6)
    - Constitution (Folder 73: 7)
    - Foreign relations - Soviet Union
      - General (Folder 73: 8)
      - Break-up of relations, 1943
        - Brochure (Folder 73: 9)
        - Clippings (Folder 73: 10)
    - Legations in the United States
      - Detroit (Folder 73: 11)
      - Los Angeles
        - General (Folder 73: 12)
        - Propaganda, 1944 July-August (Folder 73: 13)
    - Treaties, 1936-1937 (Folder 73: 14)
    - Underground peasant movement (Folder 73: 15)
  - Poles - Iran, 1943 (Folder 73: 16)
  - Sikorski, Wladyslaw (Box 74)
    - General
      - 1940 (Folder 74: 1)
      - 1941 (Folder 74: 2)
      - 1942 (Folder 74: 3)
      - ., 1943 (Folder 74: 4-7)
        Unsorted clippings from American press on Sikorski"s death and political situation following it
      - 1943 (Box-folder 75: 1-6)
      - 1943 (Box-folder 76: 1-6)
    - Biography (Box-folder 77: 1)
    - Death, 1943
      - General (Folder 77: 2-3)
      - Post mortem political moves (Folder 77: 4)
    - Gliksman, Shlomo (Folder 77: 5)
    - United States, 1942
      - General (Folder 77: 6)
      - Speeches (Folder 77: 7)
  - Soviet Union
    - General, 1944 August-September (Folder 77: 8)
    - Mission to Moscow, Hollywood film production, 1943 (Folder 77: 9)
  - Sworakowski, Witold
    - General (Folder 77: 10)
    - Clippings, 1948-1952 (Folder 77: 11)
  - Tannenberg, Battle of, 1410 (Folder 77: 12)
  - Teheran Conference and Cairo Conference and their aftermath, (1943) (1943) (Box 78)
    - 1943
      - November (Folder 78: 1-2)
      - December
        - General
        - 1-3 (Folder 78: 3-5)
        - 7-23 (Folder 78: 6)
    - 1944 January (Folder 78: 7)
  - United Nations Relief and Rehabilitation Administration, 1943-1944 (Folder 78: 8)
  - Warsaw (Poland) (Folder 79: 1)
  - We the Mothers Mobilize for America (Folder 79: 2)
  - World Citizens Association, 1940 (Folder 79: 3)
  - World War, 1939-1945
    - Anniversaries of onset
      - Fourth, 1943 (Folder 79: 4)
      - Fifth, 1944 (Folder 79: 5)
    - Atrocities, German
      - 1943 January-March (Folder 79: 6)
      - 1944 August-September (Folder 79: 7)